Samantha Dickeson (she / her)

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

A graduate of Founders and Coders, with 2+ years experience coding in Javascript. I like making things, solving problems and making things that solve problems.

I'm also a Psychology graduate, and before learning web development I worked in data analysis for four years, teaching myself SQL, VBA and a smattering of Python.

EXPERIENCE

NearSt — *Software Engineer*

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2020 - JUNIOR | JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT - MID

Working at a smaller start-up has given me the freedom to grow, learn, and take on big challenges. Our team spike out new ideas and scope our own stories, turning feature requests into technical requirements.

Within months of joining I refactored our React frontend to use hooks. I also wrote a Node serverless integration for the Square payment provider that fetched stock information for retail stores to display on Google search result pages.

I collaborated with the customer success team to build an internal tool that uses React and Node to generate PDF customer reports - massively speeding up their previous manual process. I also built a Slack workflow to request tech help, categorised by urgency, with a button for an engineer to pick up the story.

I am the lead engineer on our data pipeline, which records customer and store behaviour across thousands of shops. Working with Python, SQL & AWS I refactored our system to store and request data more efficiently. This resulted in a 10x increase in speed and 10x reduction in S3 storage costs. I also created a package of React components to allow other engineers to more easily and performantly query the data to render graphs.

Founders and Coders - Finsbury Park

MARCH 2019 - JULY 2019

At Founders and Coders I learned full-stack web development, including testing, Node, PostgresQL, Express and React.

The course had a focus on cooperation and pair programming. I also gained hands-on design and agile build sprint experience working on real-world projects.

I'M LOOKING FOR...

- £55k+ salary
- Fully remote or 3+ days remote in London
- Employers who take mental wellness seriously

STACK / SKILLS

- NodeIS
- SCSS
- AWS
- a11y & design
- React
- Express
- SQL
- Postgres
- Jest & Cypress Python

PRE-DEV EXPERIENCE

Vanguard Learning Trust, Ickenham — Data Manager DECEMBER 2015 - MARCH 2019

Xerox UK, Uxbridge — *Data* Migration Analyst MARCH 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

EDUCATION

Reading University — BSc Psychology 2:1

OCTOBER 2010 - JUNE 2014

Vyners School, Ickenham SEPTEMBER 2003 - JULY 2010

Maths A | Psychology B | Biology B



github.com/starsuit



starsuit.netlify.com



samlucydickeson@gmail.com



http://linkedin.com/in/sdickeson